Guide to the George Howard Edward Smith Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- SENATE REPUBLICAN POLICY COMMITTEE, 1932 -1960; Series III; 21 linear feet (57 boxes)
  - Subject files
    - Special reference files
      - Congress
        - Organization, 1946-1951 (Box 32, Folder 691-693)
      - Congressional campaign (1954), 1953-1954 (Box 32, Folder 694-695)
      - Congressional testimony, 1948, undated (Box 32, Folder 696)
      - Convention (1952) (Box 32, Folder 697)
      - Conventions, 1956 (Box 32, Folder 698)
      - Crisis government, 1948 (Box 32, Folder 699-700)
      - Demobilization of armed forces, 1944-1946 (Box 32, Folder 701-702)
      - Double talk: joker clauses, 1945-1947 (Box 33, Folder 703-705)
      - Economic self-containment of the U. S., 1937 (Box 33, Folder 706)
      - Elections
        - Campaign (1944), 1944-1945 (Box 33, Folder 707-709)
        - Campaign (1948) (Box 33, Folder 710-711)
        - Campaign financing, 1952-1957 (Box 33, Folder 712-714)
        - Campaign issues, 1946-1948 (Box 33, Folder 715-719)
        - Campaign issues, 1948-1956 (Box 34, Folder 720-723)
        - Campaign planning, 1952-1956 (Box 34, Folder 724-726)
        - Campaign publicity, 1947-1955 (Box 34, Folder 727-728)
        - Campaign strategy, 1949-1957 (Box 34, Folder 729-730)
        - S. 636, 1955 (Box 34, Folder 731)
        - Senatorial campaign, 1948 (Box 34, Folder 732)
      - Electoral college, 1947-1948 (Box 34, Folder 733-734)
      - Electoral college, 1949-1956 (Box 35, Folder 735-740)
      - Employment, Full: S. 380, 1945-1946 (Box 35, Folder 741)
      - Equal rights, 1941-1957 (Box 35, Folder 742)
      - Executive: influence on congress--instances of maladministration, 1945-1947 (Box 35, Folder 743-745)
      - Executive: use of crisis powers, 1937-1946 (Box 35, Folder 746-749)
      - Federal-state relations, 1957 (Box 35, Folder 750)
      - Ferguson, Homer, 1951-1954 (Box 35, Folder 751)
      - Foreign affairs and trade; foreign missions: appointments, 1945-1946 (Box 35, Folder 752)
      - Foreign Affairs and Trade, foreign Missions: appointments (cont'd), 1946 (Box 36, Folder 753)
      - Foreign affairs and trade, foreign missions: foreign policies, 1946 (Box 36, Folder 754-756)
      - Foreign policy
        - 1940s (Box 36, Folder 757)
        - 1950s (Box 36, Folder 758-761)
        - Bipartisan, 1950 (Box 36, Folder 762)
        - Dozer, Donald, 1951 (Box 36, Folder 763)
        - Geneva Convention, 1959 (Box 36, Folder 764-765)
      - General, 1947-1955 (Box 36, Folder 766)
      - Government administration
        - Aviation, 1945 (Box 36, Folder 767-768)
        - Bureaucracy, 1937-1949 (Box 36, Folder 769-772)
      - Government agency propaganda, 1945-1949 (Box 36, Folder 773)
      - Government and pressure groups, 1945-1947 (Box 36, Folder 774)
      - Government corporations, 1943-1945 (Box 37, Folder 775-777)
      - Government fee changes, 1950-1952 (Box 37, Folder 778)
      - Government operations and enterprises, 1942-1945 (Box 37, Folder 779-780)
      - Government propaganda, 1945-1947 (Box 37, Folder 781-783)
      - House of Representatives: elections (1948) (Box 37, Folder 784-785)
      - International collaboration, costs of, 1944-1947 (Box 37, Folder 786)
      - Laws
        - Campaign expenditures, 1956 (Box 37, Folder 787)
        - Political processes, 1950-1955 (Box 37, Folder 788)
        - Politics, 1951-1957 (Box 37, Folder 789)
      - Lend lease, 1944-1945 (Box 37, Folder 790)
      - Lend lease, 1945-1947 (Box 38, Folder 791-793)
      - Liberals, 1947 (Box 38, Folder 794)
      - Lobbies, 1942-1949 (Box 38, Folder 795-796)
      - McCarthy, Joseph, 1954-1957 (Box 38, Folder 797)
        - Debate on resolution by Senator Ralph Flanders, 1954 (Box 38, Folder 798)
      - Mineral policy, 1948-1949 (Box 38, Folder 799)
      - Minority activities: food, 1943-1945 (Box 38, Folder 800-801)
      - Miscellaneous, 1945-1958 (Box 38, Folder 802-806)
      - Montgomery Ward and Company, 1944 (Box 38, Folder 807-808)
      - National Science Foundation
        - Meeting of committees, 1945-1946 (Box 38, Folder 809-810)
        - Miscellaneous, 1946-1947 (Box 39, Folder 811)
        - Science bills, 1946-1947 (Box 39, Folder 812)
        - S. 1850, 1946-1947 (Box 39, Folder 813-826)
      - National Woman's Party, 1953-1957 (Box 40, Folder 827)
      - New and Fair Deals, Democratic, 1946-1956 (Box 40, Folder 828-830)
      - New Deal
        - General, 1932-1948 (Box 40, Folder 831-839)
        - General, 1946-1949 (Box 41, Folder 840-851)
        - General, 1945 (Box 42, Folder 852-854)
        - "Big Government", 1948-1952 (Box 42, Folder 855-857)
        - Personnel, 1945-1947 (Box 42, Folder 858-859)
        - Political cartoons, 1945-1949 (Box 42, Folder 860-864)
        - Congressional criticisms of, 1948 (Box 42, Folder 865)
      - Office of Price Administration
        - "Folder no.1", 1946 (Box 42, Folder 866)
        - "Folder no. 2 - 10", 1946 (Box 43, Folder 867-882)
        - Miscellaneous pamphlets, 1946 (Box 44, Folder 883-884)
      - Parties, minor, 1954-1956 (Box 44, Folder 885)
      - Parties, realignment of, 1951-1952 (Box 44, Folder 886)
      - Party differences, 1953-1955 (Box 44, Folder 887-888)
      - Party organization
        - In Congress, 1954-1956 (Box 44, Folder 889)
        - State and local, 1954-1957 (Box 44, Folder 890-891)
      - Party roles and responsibilities, 1951-1959 (Box 44, Folder 892-894)
      - Party strategy in Congress, 1954-1957 (Box 44, Folder 895-896)
      - Patronage, 1955-1956 (Box 44, Folder 897)
      - Patterns of Legislation: preamble study:
        - Titles, 1945-1946 (Box 44, Folder 898-899)
        - Legislation enacted, 79-1, 1945 (Box 45, Folder 900)
        - Legislation enacted, 79-2, 1945 (Box 45, Folder 901)
        - Legislation not enacted, 79-1, 1945 (Box 45, Folder 902-905)
        - Legislation not enacted, 79-2, 1946 (Box 45, Folder 906-907)
      - Patterns of Legislation: U. S. Congress
        - 78th Congress, 1st Session, 1943 (Box 45, Folder 908)
        - 78th Congress, 2nd Session, 1944 (Box 45, Folder 909)
        - 79th Congress, 1st Session, 1945 (Box 45, Folder 910)
        - 79th Congress, 2nd Session, 1946 (Box 45, Folder 911-912)
      - Patterns of Legislation: U. S. Congress, 80th Congress, first session
        - Agriculture, 1947 (Box 46, Folder 913)
        - Education (Box 46, Folder 914)
        - Health, 1947 (Box 46, Folder 915-918)
        - Industry, 1947 (Box 46, Folder 919)
        - Miscellaneous, 1947 (Box 46, Folder 920)
        - National economy, 1947 (Box 46, Folder 921)
        - Public welfare (Box 46, Folder 921)
          - Recreation, 1947 (Box 46, Folder 922)
          - Security, 1947 (Box 46, Folder 923-925)
        - Veterans, 1947 (Box 46, Folder 926)
        - Unidentified, 1947 (Box 46, Folder 927)
      - Patterns of Legislation: U. S. Congress, 81st Congress, first session
        - Education, 1949 (Box 46, Folder 927)
        - General, 1949 (Box 46, Folder 928)
        - Labor extension, 1949 (Box 47, Folder 929)
        - Library demonstrations, 1949 (Box 47, Folder 930)
        - Health
          - Arthritis research, 1949 (Box 47, Folder 931)
          - Cerebral palsy research, 1949 (Box 47, Folder 932)
          - Dental aids, 1949 (Box 47, Folder 933)
          - Epilepsy research, 1949 (Box 47, Folder 934)
          - Federal Commission on Physically Handicapped, 1949 (Box 47, Folder 935-936)
          - Leprosy, 1949 (Box 47, Folder 937)
          - Miscellaneous, 1949 (Box 47, Folder 938)
          - Mobilization of cancer experts, 1949 (Box 47, Folder 939)
          - Multiple disease research, 1949 (Box 47, Folder 940)
          - Multiple sclerosis research, 1949 (Box 47, Folder 941)
          - Socialized medicine, 1949 (Box 47, Folder 942-943)
        - Housing, 1949 (Box 47, Folder 944)
        - Industry: Veterans Development Corporation, 1949 (Box 47, Folder 945-946)
        - National resources, 1949 (Box 47, Folder 947-948)
        - Public welfare: Youth programs, 1949 (Box 47, Folder 949-950)
        - Public works, 1949 (Box 47, Folder 951)
      - Patterns of Legislation: U. S. Congress, Auxiliary bills
        - Health, 1947 (Box 47, Folder 952)
        - Industry, 1947 (Box 47, Folder 953)
        - National economy, 1947 (Box 47, Folder 954)
        - Public welfare-security, 1947 (Box 47, Folder 955)
        - Miscellaneous, 1947 (Box 47, Folder 956)
      - Philippines, 1932 (Box 47, Folder 957)
      - Philippines (cont'd), 1932-1933 (Box 48, Folder 958)
      - Point Four Program, 1950-1951 (Box 48, Folder 959)
      - Policy questions, 1944-1949 (Box 48, Folder 960-962)
      - Political groups: unofficial, 1946-1955 (Box 48, Folder 963)
      - Political issues: clippings, 1950-1951 (Box 48, Folder 964-966)
      - Political literature: miscellaneous, 1946-1952 (Box 48, Folder 967-971)
      - Political literature: miscellaneous (cont 'd), 1946-1960 (Box 49, Folder 972-975)
      - Political parties: American (General and Historical), 1951-1958 (Box 49, Folder 976-978)
      - Political party material: 81st Congress, 1948 (Box 49, Folder 979)
      - Political party platforms
        - Douglas, William O., 1948 (Box 49, Folder 980-981)
        - Legislative budget, 1945-1949 (Box 49, Folder 982-983)
      - Political strategy: Executive branch vs. congress, 1954-1957 (Box 49, Folder 984)
      - Political systems: America, 1954-1957 (Box 49, Folder 985-986)
      - Political systems: comparative, 1950-1955 (Box 49, Folder 987)
      - Political thought and institutions, 1947-1957 (Box 49, Folder 988-989)
      - Political tricks, 1945-1946 (Box 49, Folder 990-991)
      - Political tricks (cont'd), 1945-1946 (Box 50, Folder 992-993)
      - Politics
        - General, 1951-1959 (Box 50, Folder 994-995)
        - Bibliography and notes, undated (Box 50, Folder 996)
        - Gaining experience, 1950-1957 (Box 50, Folder 997)
        - Illustrations, 1953-1954 (Box 50, Folder 998)
        - Miscellaneous, 1958-1959 (Box 50, Folder 999-1001)
        - Political parties--1940 campaign and Wilkie Build-up (Box 50, Folder 1002)
      - Politics and labor organizations, 1946-1956 (Box 50, Folder 1003-1005)
      - Politics and minorities, 1955 (Box 50, Folder 1006)
      - Politics and pressure groups, 1950-1956 (Box 50, Folder 1007-1009)
      - Politics as a career, 1951-1957 (Box 50, Folder 1010-1011)
      - Politics as a career, 1955-1957 (Box 51, Folder 1012-1013)
      - Politics in Congress
        - Senate and House, 1958 (Box 51, Folder 1014)
        - Investigations, 1954-1955 (Box 51, Folder 1015)
      - Polls, 1948-1956 (Box 51, Folder 1016-1021)
      - Population data, 1955 (Box 51, Folder 1022)
      - Presidential campaign
        - 1952, 1952-1954 (Box 51, Folder 1023-1026)
        - 1956, 1954-1956 (Box 51, Folder 1027-1028)
      - Pressure groups, 1957 (Box 52, Folder 1029)
      - Prices: subsidies, 1943-1947 (Box 52, Folder 1030)
      - Primary statistics, 1948 (Box 52, Folder 1031-1032)
      - Public opinion: Truman build-up, 1945 (Box 52, Folder 1033-1034)
      - Public opinion manipulation
        - Mobilizing public opinion, 1944-1947 (Box 52, Folder 1035-1037)
        - U. N. charter, 1945 (Box 52, Folder 1038-1040)
      - Reclamation, 1947-1948 (Box 52, Folder 1041-1042)
      - Republican Committee on Programs and Progress, 1959 (Box 52, Folder 1043)
      - Republican freedom vs. New Deal regimentation, 1946-1947 (Box 52, Folder 1044)
      - Republican party
        - General, 1948-1957 (Box 52, Folder 1045-1046)
        - General (cont'd), 1954-1955 (Box 53, Folder 1047)
        - Mundt proposal, 1951 (Box 53, Folder 1048)
        - Record, 1954-1957 (Box 53, Folder 1049-1053)
        - Record in 79th Congress, 1945-1946 (Box 53, Folder 1054-1055)
      - Republican Policy Committee: miscellaneous, 1951-1957 (Box 53, Folder 1056-1057)
      - Republican politics, 1944-1947 (Box 53, Folder 1058-1061)
      - Republican position, 1944-1952 (Box 53, Folder 1062)
      - Roosevelt, Franklin Delano, 1944-1945 (Box 53, Folder 1063)
      - Science legislation, 1945-1948 (Box 54, Folder 1064-1065)
        - Speeches: drafts, [1946-1948?] (Box 54, Folder 1066)
        - Speeches: Congressional Record, 1946-1947 (Box 54, Folder 1067)
      - Science research bills: 79th Congress, 1945-1946 (Box 54, Folder 1068-1069)
      - Staffing and operations:
        - General, 1945-1960 (Box 54, Folder 1070)
        - Budget and financial statements, 1946-1951 (Box 54, Folder 1071-1073)
        - Republican administrative assistants and secretaries staff association, 1947-1957 (Box 54, Folder 1074)
        - Republican Policy Committee and staff, 1949-1960 (Box 54, Folder 1075)
        - Staff lists, 1949-1958 (Box 54, Folder 1076)
      - State governors (1948) (Box 55, Folder 1077)
      - Stories, 1946-1947 (Box 55, Folder 1078)
      - Subversives, control of, 1950 (Box 55, Folder 1079-1081)
      - Tariff, 1948-1950 (Box 55, Folder 1082)
      - Truman-Meade Committee reports, 1942-1943 (Box 55, Folder 1083-1084)
      - Truman-Meade Committee reports (cont'd), 1944-1945 (Box 56, Folder 1085-1086)
      - United Nations
        - General, 1949-1950 (Box 56, Folder 1087-1090)
        - Relief, 1945 (Box 56, Folder 1091)
      - United States: composition, 1955-1958 (Box 56, Folder 1092)
      - Volunteers and committees, 1956 (Box 56, Folder 1093)
      - Voting
        - Behavior, 1955-1957 (Box 56, Folder 1094)
        - Charts, 1956 (Box 56, Folder 1095)
        - Statistics, 1948-1958 (Box 56, Folder 1096-1097)
  - Minutes
    - Drafts
      - 1944 March - 1946 December (Box 57, Folder 1098-1105)
      - 1947 January - 1948 August (Box 58, Folder 1106-1112)
    - Conference copies
      - 1944 April - 1945 December (Box 59, Folder 1113-1117)
      - 1946 January - 1948 August (Box 60, Folder 1118-1125)
  - Printed material
    - 1945-1951 (Box 61, Folder 1126-1131)
    - 1952-1957 (Box 62, Folder 1132-1137)
    - 1959, undated (Box 63, Folder 1138-1142)
- WRITINGS, 1926-1959; Series IV; 5 linear feet (14 boxes)
  This series is arranged in the following sections: Books-drafts, Books miscellaneous, Books-reference files, Books-research notes, Articles, Speeches, Book reviews, and Miscellaneous.
  All sections are arranged alphabetically by title or topic with the exceptions of Articles, Speeches, and Book reviews.
  Articles are arranged alphabetically by the journal of publication.
  Speeches and Book reviews are arranged chronologically.
  - Books - drafts
    - American Government and Politics (Box 64, Folder 1143)
    - The American Party System (Box 64, Folder 1144-1145)
    - The Art of National Politics
      - notes (Box 64, Folder 1146-1147)
      - Proposal, 1953 (Box 64, Folder 1148)
    - Congress and Defense (Box 64, Folder 1149-1150)
    - The Future Comes: A Study of the New Deal (Box 64, Folder 1151)
    - Idea of National Interest --1st Draft, Chapters I - X (Box 65, Folder 1152-1158)
    - Idea of National Interest --1st Draft (cont'd) Chapters XI - XII (Box 66, Folder 1159)
    - Idea of National Interest --Final Draft (Box 66, Folder 1160-1163)
    - The Open Door at Home --1st Draft (Box 66, Folder 1164-1167)
    - The Open Door at Home --1st Draft Chapter XIII (Box 67, Folder 1168)
    - The Open Door at Home --2nd Draft (Box 67, Folder 1169-1172)
    - Practical Politics and Political Campaigning: A Bibliography, notes (Box 67, Folder 1173)
    - Practical Economics-- Part I --Draft
      - Version A
        - Chapters I - II (Box 67, Folder 1174)
        - Chapters I - III, pp. 1-74 (Box 67, Folder 1175)
      - Version B
        - Chapters I - II (Box 67, Folder 1176)
    - Raw Material Situation of the United States (Box 67, Folder 1177-1181)
  - Books-Miscellaneous
    - Foreign Policy in a Twentieth Century World --outline (Box 68, Folder 1182)
    - Commodities in the Foreign Trade of an American National Economy (Box 68, Folder 1183)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 68, Folder 1184-1186)
  - Books--reference files
    - Economic Principles (Box 69, Folder 1187)
    - International security (Box 69, Folder 1188-1192)
    - Special Studies--National Interest
      - Bibliography (Box 69, Folder 1193)
      - Capitalism and Economic Development (Box 69, Folder 1194)
      - Enforcement (Box 69, Folder 1195-1196)
      - Intergovernmental debts (Box 69, Folder 1197)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 69, Folder 1198)
      - National Wealth and Income (Box 69, Folder 1199)
      - Philosophy (Box 69, Folder 1200)
      - World system (Box 69, Folder 1201)
  - Books--research notes
    - Economics;Access to Raw Materials and Access to Investment Opportunities (Box 70, Folder 1201)
    - Security; Miscellaneous (Box 71, Folder 1201)
  - Articles
    - Current History, 1941 (Box 72, Folder 1202-1203)
    - Foundation for Foreign Affairs, 1950 (Box 72, Folder 1204)
    - Founders and Leaders of Connecticut
      - notes and first draft, pre-1933 (Box 72, Folder 1205-1206)
      - Final draft, 1933 (Box 72, Folder 1207)
    - Harper's, 1942 (Box 72, Folder 1208)
    - Plain Talk Magazine, 1929-1930 (Box 72, Folder 1209)
    - The Social Studies, 1934-1936 (Box 72, Folder 1210-1225)
    - World Unity, 1931 (Box 72, Folder 1226)
    - Miscellaneous articles and editorials, 1927-1930 (Box 72, Folder 1227)
    - Unpublished writings
      - n.d. (Box 72, Folder 1228-1229)
      - 1940 (Box 72, Folder 1230)
    - "What Are We Going to Do About Propaganda?", undated (Box 72, Folder 1231)
    - "Topics of the Month in World Affairs", undated (Box 72, Folder 1232)
  - Speeches
    - Correspondence, 1934-1959 (Box 73, Folder 1233-1242)
    - Texts and notes, 1926-1938 (Box 73, Folder 1243-1269)
    - Texts and notes, 1938-1947 (Box 74, Folder 1270-1317)
    - Texts and notes, 1947-1959,undated (Box 75, Folder 1318-1365)
  - Book Reviews, 1927-1951 (Box 76, Folder 1366-1371)
  - Writings-Miscellaneous
    - "Access to Investment Opportunities" (I. I. R.) (Box 77, Folder 1372-1373)
    - "Border Problems of the United States" (I. I. R.) (Box 77, Folder 1374)
    - notes (Box 77, Folder 1375)
    - "Consumer's Boycotts in Europe", 1933 (Box 77, Folder 1376)
    - Handbook of Post-War Planning, Preliminary memo, 1943 (Box 77, Folder 1377)
    - Memo on the Polish Corridor
      - 1st draft, post-1934 (Box 77, Folder 1378)
      - Final draft (Box 77, Folder 1379)
    - Memo on the U. S. and Sino-Japanese Controversy (Box 77, Folder 1380)
    - Memorandum on the Boycott (Box 77, Folder 1381)
    - "Modes of Contact and Communication Between Continental United States and Foreign Countries" (Box 77, Folder 1382)
    - "Politics and the Trend of the Times" (Box 77, Folder 1383)
    - The Recovery Program
      - 1st draft (Box 77, Folder 1384)
      - 2nd draft (Box 77, Folder 1385)
      - 3rd draft (Box 77, Folder 1386)
      - Final draft and printed copy, 1934 (Box 77, Folder 1387)
    - "Security" (Box 77, Folder 1388)
    - "United States Basic Commodities..." (Box 77, Folder 1389)
- STUDENT PAPERS, TEACHING MATERIALS AND PERSONAL PAPERS, 1917-1959; Series V; 2.5 linear feet (5 boxes)
  This series is arranged in three sections: Student papers, Teaching materials, and Personal papers.
  Each section is arranged alphabetically. Student papers and Teaching materials are organized by the educational institution, and Personal papers according to the individual.
  - Student papers
    - University of Michigan (Box 78)
      - Lecture notes, 1927-1928 (Box 78, Folder 1390)
      - Student papers, 1928-1929 (Box 78, Folder 1391-1392)
    - Yale University
      - notes, 1935-1936 (Box 78, Folder 1393)
      - Student papers, 1936 (Box 78, Folder 1394-1395)
  - Teaching material (Box 79)
    - Yale University
      - Correspondence
        - Bibliography 100, 1938-1941 (Box 79, Folder 1396)
        - General, 1936-1940 (Box 79, Folder 1397)
        - Government 36, 1938-1941 (Box 79, Folder 1398)
        - Graduate school, 1935 (Box 79, Folder 1399)
      - notes
        - Bibliography 100 (Box 79, Folder 1400-1401)
        - Government 36 (Box 79, Folder 1402-1403)
    - Yale University, New Haven, YMCA Jr. College
      - Correspondence
        - Economics Course, 1932-1944 (Box 79, Folder 1404-1406)
        - Engineering, science, management war training program, 1932-1944 (Box 79, Folder 1407-1408)
        - Post-war planning, 1932-1944 (Box 79, Folder 1409)
        - Administrative papers, 1938-1944 (Box 80, Folder 1410)
        - Course outlines, schedules, card notes, 1934-1945 (Box 80, Folder 1411-1412)
        - College examinations, 1933-1944 (Box 80, Folder 1413-1415)
    - Yale University--New Haven Jr. College
      - "Labor-Management Relations" material (Box 80, Folder 1416)
      - Lecture notes, 1933-1944 (Box 80, Folder 1417-1419)
    - U. S. Dept of Agriculture (Box 80, Folder 1420)
      - Graduate school, course outlines
        - Lectures and notes, 1949 (Box 80, Folder 1421)
        - Memoranda, 1948-1949 (Box 80, Folder 1422)
  - Personal Papers
    - George H. E. Smith (Box 81)
      - Name change, 1918 (Box 81, Folder 1423)
      - Photographs and miscellaneous, 1944, undated (Box 81, Folder 1424)
      - Resumes, Circa 1932-1959 (Box 81, Folder 1425)
      - Selective service registration, 1917, 1942 (Box 81, Folder 1426)
      - Smith, Lewish J., death of, 1945 (Box 81, Folder 1427)
    - Elizabeth Wehner Smith, 1930-1931, undated (Box 82, Folder 1428-1430)
    - Mary Smith (Box 82, Folder 1431)
    - Nancy Smith (Box 82, Folder 1432)